nycourts.gov 2018-12-16

# Privacy - N.Y. State Courts

Internet Web Site Privacy Policy 

* * *

**INTRODUCTION**

Thank you for visiting the New York State Unified Court System’s (UCS) web site at [ www.courts.state.ny.us ](http://www.courts.state.ny.us/) . This web site is designed to make it easier and more efficient for the public to interact with the UCS. The UCS recognizes that it is critical for members of the public to be confident that their privacy is protected when they visit the UCS web site and that they are aware of any possible uses of personal information. 

Consistent with the provisions of the New York State Internet Security and Privacy Act, State Technology Law 201 et. seq., this policy describes the UCS’s practices regarding information collected from users of this web site. This policy describes what information is collected and how that information is used. Because this privacy policy applies only to this web site, you should examine the privacy policy of other web sites that you access using links from this web site. 

**The UCS does not collect any personal information about you unless you provide that information voluntarily by sending an e-mail or by initiating an online transaction such as a survey, registration, or order form.**

Use of this web site signifies agreement with the terms of this policy. 

* * *

For complete details regarding this policy see the following: 

Information Collected Automatically at this Web Site    
Information Collected Through E-mails and Online Transactions    
Information and Choice    
Disclosure of Information Collected    
Retention of Information Collected    
Access To and Correction of Personal Information    
Confidentiality and Integrity of Personal Information    
Information Disclaimer    
Contact Information 

* * *

** INFORMATION COLLECTED AUTOMATICALLY WHEN YOU VISIT THIS WEB SITE **

When you visit this web site, the UCS automatically collects and stores the following information about your visit: 

(i) The Internet Protocol Address and domain name used, but not the e-mail address. The Internet Protocol Address is a numerical identifier assigned either to your Internet service provider or directly to your computer; 

(ii) The type of browser and operating system you used; 

(iii) The date and time you visit this site; 

(iv) The web pages or services you accessed at this site; 

(v) The web site you visited prior to coming to this web site; 

(vi) The web site you visit as you leave this web site; and 

(vii) Any form or information that you downloaded. 

None of the foregoing information is deemed to constitute personal information. 

The information that is collected automatically is used to improve this web site’s content and to help the UCS understand how users are interacting with the web site. This information is collected for statistical analysis, to determine what information is of most and least interest to users of the site and to improve the utility of the material available on the web site. This information is not collected for commercial marketing purposes, and the UCS is not authorized to sell or otherwise disclose the information collected from the web site for commercial purposes. 

back to top

* * *

** INFORMATION COLLECTED WHEN YOU E-MAIL THIS WEB SITE OR INITIATE AN ONLINE TRANSACTION **

During your visit to this web site you may send an e-mail to the UCS. Your e-mail address and the contents of your message will be collected. The information collected is not limited to text characters and may include audio, video and graphic information formats included in the message. Your e-mail address and the information included in your message will be used to respond to you, to address issues you identify, to improve this web site, or, where appropriate, to forward your message to another public agency for follow-up. Your e-mail address is not collected for commercial purposes, and the UCS is not authorized to sell or otherwise disclose your e-mail address for commercial purposes. 

During your visit to this web site you may initiate a transaction such as a survey, registration or order. The information, including personal information, volunteered by you in initiating the transaction is used by the UCS to operate UCS programs, which may include the provision of goods, services and information. The information collected by the UCS may be disclosed by the UCS for those purposes that may be reasonably ascertained from the nature and terms of the transaction in connection with which the information was submitted. (For example, responses to a survey regarding the operation of the UCS web site may be used to improve services offered on the web site.) Except for ongoing voluntary transactions, the UCS does not store information that allows the web site to recognize users when they visit the web site again. 

The UCS, in general, does not knowingly collect personal information from children or create profiles of children through this web site. To the extent that UCS provides the opportunity for children to e-mail questions or comments, the UCS does not share the information received with third parties or create profiles of children using such information. Users are cautioned, however, that, other than in a special program directed at questions and comments by children, the collection of personal information submitted in an e-mail will be treated as though it was submitted by an adult, and may, unless exempted from access by federal or State law, be subject to public access. The UCS strongly encourages parents, guardians, and teachers to be involved in children’s Internet activities and to provide guidance whenever children are asked to provide personal information online. 

back to top

* * *

** INFORMATION AND CHOICE **

As noted above, the UCS does not collect any personal information about you during your visit to this web site unless you provide that information voluntarily by sending an e-mail or initiating an online transaction such as a survey, registration or order. You may choose not to send an e-mail, respond to a survey, or complete an order form. While your choice not to participate in these activities may limit your ability to receive specific services, products, publications, or information through this web site, it will not prevent you from requesting services, products, publications, or information from UCS by other means and will not normally have an impact on your ability to take advantage of other features of the web site, including browsing or downloading publicly available information. 

back to top

* * *

** DISCLOSURE OF INFORMATION COLLECTED THROUGH THIS WEB SITE **

The collection of information through this web site and the disclosure of that information are subject to the provisions of the New York State Internet Security and Privacy Act, State Technology Law 201 et. seq. and other applicable law. The UCS will collect personal information through this web site or disclose personal information collected through this web site only if the user has consented to the collection or disclosure of such personal information. The voluntary disclosure of personal information to the UCS by the user, whether solicited or unsolicited, constitutes consent to the collection and disclosure of the information by the UCS for the purposes for which the user disclosed the information to the UCS, as reasonably ascertainable from the nature and terms of the disclosure. 

For example, the use of the UCS Case Trac and Filing by Electronic Means services involves the voluntary provision of personal information for billing and other purposes. UCS does not sell or give this information to anyone. The UCS may, however, use the information collected in connection with Case Trac, Filing by Electronic Means and similar services internally to market other UCS products and services. 

However, the UCS may collect or disclose personal information without user consent if the collection or disclosure is: (1) necessary to perform the statutory duties of the UCS, or necessary for the UCS to operate a program authorized by law, or authorized by state or federal statute or regulation; (2) made pursuant to a court order or by law; (3) for the purpose of validating the identity of the user; or (4) of information to be used solely for statistical purposes that is in a form that cannot be used to identify any particular person. 

The UCS may disclose personal information to federal or state law enforcement authorities in the course of officially authorized law enforcement investigations or to enforce the UCS’s rights against unauthorized access or attempted unauthorized access to the UCS’s information technology assets (for example, to protect against hackers). 

back to top

* * *

** RETENTION OF INFORMATION COLLECTED THROUGH THE WEB SITE **

The information collected through this web site is retained by the UCS in accordance with the records retention and disposition requirements contained in Part 104 of the Rules of the Chief Administrator of the Courts. Information on those requirements may be found on this web site at [ http://www.nycourts.gov/rules/chiefadmin/104.shtml ](http://www.nycourts.gov/rules/chiefadmin/104.shtml) . 

back to top

* * *

** ACCESS TO AND CORRECTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION COLLECTED THROUGH THIS WEB SITE **

Any user of those services that collect personal information may obtain access to and correct information provided through mechanisms established by those services. 

back to top

* * *

** CONFIDENTIALITY AND INTEGRITY OF PERSONAL INFORMATION COLLECTED THROUGH THIS WEB SITE **

The UCS is strongly committed to protecting personal information collected through this web site against unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. Consequently, the UCS limits employee access to personal information collected through this web site to only those employees who need access to the information in the performance of their official duties. Employees who have access to this information are required to follow appropriate procedures in connection with any disclosures of personal information. 

In addition, UCS has implemented procedures to safeguard the integrity of its information technology assets, including but not limited to, authentication, monitoring, auditing, and encryption. These security procedures have been integrated into the design, implementation, and day-to-day operations of this web site as part of a continuing commitment to the security of electronic content as well as the electronic transmission of information. 

For web site security purposes and to maintain the availability of the web site for all users, the UCS employs software to monitor traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information or otherwise damage this web site. 

back to top

* * *

** INFORMATION DISCLAIMER **

The information provided in this privacy policy should not be construed as giving business, legal, or other advice, or warranting as fail-proof, the security of information provided through this web site. 

Information provided on this web site is intended to allow the public convenient electronic access to public information. While all attempts are made to provide accurate, current, and reliable information, the UCS recognizes the possibility of human or mechanical error. Therefore, the UCS, its employees, officers, and agencies make no representations as to the accuracy, completeness, currency or suitability of the information provided by this web site and disclaim any express or implied warranty as to the same. 

back to top

* * *

** CONTACT INFORMATION **   
For questions regarding this Internet privacy policy, please contact: 

By E-mail: [ pyow@nycourts.gov ](mailto:pyow@nycourts.gov)

By Regular Mail:   
New York State Unified Court System   
Office of Court Administration   
25 Beaver Street   
New York, NY 10004   
Attention: Phillip Yow, Website Systems Director 

back to top
